Christopher Travis Williams, BBA

720.469.5080|Chris.T.Williams417@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

Develop sustainable relationships with clients that bring mutual benefit to both parties. Ensure that sales services and products are top of mind for clients or potential customer. Provide unique, high-quality service for customers so they return and recommend my services to their network. Accumulate and evolve skills outside the home office and work with top leading experts in the industry.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Baruch Construction Inc

Lakewood, CO

Outside Sales Representative

March 2021-July 2022

- Developed client relationships that fostered trust in their home improvement projects
- Created and applied a consultative sales process to ensure high closing percentage
- Provided solutions on all aspects of claims process
- Worked extensively with a CRM to create efficient record of client interactions
- Built relationships with referral partners

Valor Roof and Solar

Sheridan, CO

Senior Project Manager

February 2019 – December 2020

- Maintained a 50% closing ratio on all sales appointments
- \$700,000 in roofing and upgrade sales annually
- Created effective sales presentations and estimates using a consultative sales approach
- Successfully negotiated cost of projects with client and insurance carriers
- Responsible for accurately ordering all materials for construction and organizing delivery
- Managed construction crew from start to completion of all projects
- Consistently reached and exceeded company target profit margins

Vivax Pros Denver, CO

Senior Sales Representative

January 2011 – December 2018

- Average annual sales totaled \$1,100,000
- Averaged 800 in home presentations per year
- Bid and negotiated projects to specific dollar amounts while hitting the companies target profit
 margins
- Guided clients through color and design process
- Implemented successful follow up system to secure jobs not closed at initial meeting
- Emphasis on consultative sales approach based on quality over lowest price
- Attended and led weekly team building exercises

EDUCATION

Texas Tech University, Rawls College of Business

Lubbock, TX

Bachelor of Business Administration in Marketing

December 2007

Bachelor of Business Administration in Management

December 2007